A Guide to the Shane Miller Collection, 1968-1969
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
Shane Miller Collection, 1968-1969
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll. 28
1.2 Linear Feet 3 boxes.
Miller, Shane; Tomlin, Fred
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by material type.
Biographical / Historical
Richard Shane Miller was born on January 25, 1907 in Reading, Pennsylvania to Benjamin F. Miller and Edith Shane. Miller worked as a commercial artist and an animated cartoon illustrator, employed by Paramount Pictures, Los Angeles, California, and Max Fleischer Studios in Miami, Florida.
He was a co-founder of the Association for Research and Enlightenment New York Center in 1950. He participated in New York Center activities for over 20 years. He served as a regional representative and a speaker before moving to Australia to study with Raynor Johnson. Miller moved moved to Virginia Beach after his wife Janet's death.
He created an illustrated slide presentation entitled "The Story of Revelation" with Fred Tomlin of Tomlin Films (New York City) from 1968-1969. He contributed art to Venture Inward Magazine. Miller wrote books including Desert Fighter: The Story of General Yigael Yadin and the Dead Sea Scrolls (1967); The Bible as a Handbook for Understanding Self (1963); and Dreams: The Language of the Unconscious, co-authored with Hugh Lynn Cayce and Tom C. Clark (1971).
Shane Miller died in Virginia Beach on November 26, 1992 at the age of 85.
Custodial History
The E.C.F. accessioned this collection from another location on the A.R.E. campus on January 19, 1989.
Related Materials
Slides from presentation located in the E.C.F. Photography Collection.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes audiotape, draft materials, painted illustrations, and scripts for Shane Miller's slide presentation "The Story of Revelation," produced in association with Tomlin Films from 1968-1969. Douglass B. Tomlin, Fred Tomlin, and Ray Owens of Tomlin Films also worked on the project.
- Box 1, Miller, Shane
  - audiotapes (2) The Story of Revelation, 1968-1969; Item 1:1
  - cue script [The Story of Revelation], 1968-1969; Folder 1:2
  - cue script labels, 1968-1969; Folder 1:3
  - galley proofs for credit titles, 1969; Folder 1:4
  - kodaliths [scene 7B], 1968-1969; Folder 1:5
  - kodaliths [scene 45], 1968-1969; Folder 1:6
  - kodaliths [The Experiences of Collective Man / John's Experiences], 1968-1969; Folder 1:7
  - labels [part one], 1968-1969; Folder 1:8
  - labels [part two], 1968-1969; Folder 1:9
  - lettering [scene 17], 1968-1969; Folder 1:10
  - lettering [scene 25], 1968-1969; Folder 1:11
  - lettering [scene 26], 1968-1969; Folder 1:12
  - letterpress copy [25A; 25B; body diagrams], 1968-1969; Folder 1:13
  - letterpress copy for titles, 1968-1969; Folder 1:14
  - painting [scene 5], 1968-1969; Folder 1:15
  - painting [scene 7], 1968-1969; Folder 1:16
  - painting [scene 8], 1968-1969; Folder 1:17
  - painting [scene 9], 1968-1969; Folder 1:18
  - painting [scene 10], 1968-1969; Folder 1:19
  - painting [scene 11], 1968-1969; Folder 1:20
  - painting [scene 12], 1968-1969; Folder 1:21
  - painting [scene 13], 1968-1969; Folder 1:22
  - painting [scene 14], 1968-1969; Folder 1:23
  - painting [scene 17], 1968-1969; Folder 1:24
  - painting [scene 22], 1968-1969; Folder 1:25
  - painting [scene 24], 1968-1969; Folder 1:26
  - painting [scene 25A], 1968-1969; Folder 1:27
  - painting [scene 25B], 1968-1969; Folder 1:28
  - painting [scene 27], 1968-1969; Folder 1:29
  - painting [scene 28], 1968-1969; Folder 1:30
  - painting [scene 29], 1968-1969; Folder 1:31
  - painting [scene 30], 1968-1969; Folder 1:32
  - painting [scene 31], 1968-1969; Folder 1:33
  - painting [scene 32], 1968-1969; Folder 1:34
  - painting [scene 33], 1968-1969; Folder 1:35
  - painting [scene 34], 1968-1969; Folder 1:36
  - painting [scene 35], 1968-1969; Folder 1:37
  - painting [scene 36], 1968-1969; Folder 1:38
  - painting [scene 37], 1968-1969; Folder 1:39
- Box 2, Miller, Shane
  - painting [scene 38], 1968-1969; Folder 2:1
  - painting [scene 39], 1968-1969; Folder 2:2
  - painting [scene 40], 1968-1969; Folder 2:3
  - painting [scenes 41-44 with overlay], 1968-1969; Folder 2:4
  - painting [scene 41A], 1968-1969; Folder 2:5
  - painting [scene 41B], 1968-1969; Folder 2:6
  - painting [scene 42], 1968-1969; Folder 2:7
  - painting [scene 43], 1968-1969; Folder 2:8
  - painting [scene 45], 1968-1969; Folder 2:9
  - painting [scene 46], 1968-1969; Folder 2:10
  - painting [scene 47], 1968-1969; Folder 2:11
  - painting [scene 48], 1968-1969; Folder 2:12
  - painting [scene 49], 1968-1969; Folder 2:13
  - painting [scene 50], 1968-1969; Folder 2:14
  - painting [scene 51], 1968-1969; Folder 2:15
  - painting [scene 52], 1968-1969; Folder 2:16
  - painting [scene 53], 1968-1969; Folder 2:17
  - painting [scene 54', 1968-1969; Folder 2:18
  - painting [scene 56], 1968-1969; Folder 2:19
  - painting [scene 57-68], 1968-1969; Folder 2:20
  - painting [scene 58], 1968-1969; Folder 2:21
  - painting [scene 59], 1968-1969; Folder 2:22
  - painting [scene 60], 1968-1969; Folder 2:23
  - painting [scene 61], 1968-1969; Folder 2:24
  - painting [scene 62], 1968-1969; Folder 2:25
  - painting [scene 63], 1968-1969; Folder 2:26
  - painting [scene 64], 1968-1969; Folder 2:27
  - painting [scene 65], 1968-1969; Folder 2:28
  - painting [scene 66], 1968-1969; Folder 2:29
  - painting [scene 67], 1968-1969; Folder 2:30
  - script, 1968-1969; Folder 2:31
  - script [original], 1968; Folder 2:32
  - script [working], 1968; Folder 2:33
  - slide [chapter 22], 1968-1969; Folder 2:34
  - storyboards, 1968-1969; Folder 2:35
  - worksheets, 1968-1969; Folder 2:36
- Box 3, Miller, Shane
  - kodalith prints, 1968-1969; Folder 3:1-3:8
  - painting [scenes 19; 20; 26], 1968-1969; Item 3:9
  - painting [scenes 15; 18], 1968-1969; Item 3:10
  - painting [scenes 1-3; 4; 6; 23; 69; 70; epilogue], 1968-1969; Item 3:11